Wonderful moment of praise and the
worship.
Hallelujah. Hallelujah. Hallelujah.
Amen. Amen. Amen. Can we release the
praise and the worship team? God bless
you.
That's wonderful.
Uh yeah, before you sit down, shake the
hand of the person close to you.
Tell them welcome to this evening's
service.
The Lord is here and he's going to do us
good.
Bible says, "Wherever you went
what did he do?"
Did good. And so he is here and he's
going to do good to us. To the glory and
honor of his name.
Amen.
Amen. Hope every one of us is enjoying
the week.
Uh we thank God cuz uh
everything
is under his control.
And we want to bless his name because
God is forever
mighty, powerful, and glorious. So, it
doesn't matter what's going on. We are
in safe hands. Praise the Lord.
And all is well to the glory and honor
of his name.
Um before I preach, I want us to
appreciate our father,
the prophet of the house, our bishop,
in his absentia. Amen.
[applause and cheering]
Amen. We want also to appreciate our
mom.
Uh she's not here, but we thank God for
her.
She supported this man of God and uh
made sure that the vision the man of God
saw many years ago continued. We thank
God for that. And I want to appreciate
the pastors who are here with us. Can we
appreciate the servants of the Lord who
are with us here? God bless you. You're
very important
as men and women of God
uh in the
work the Lord has given us. As we pray
for one another, as we counsel each
other, and we as we encourage one
another, we thank God for you people.
And then can we appreciate ourselves for
for you people. And then, can we
appreciate ourselves for coming
this evening to the day's service. Amen.
You are very important, and I know
God has brought us here for a divine
purpose.
Uh this evening,
I want us
uh to
trust the Lord that is going to
encourage us.
Uh we're living at a time when so many
people are living a life of
discouragement.
So many people are discouraged
by so many things.
So many people are going through hard
moments.
Some are having sleepless nights
because of the pressure they have either
within or without.
And tonight, we want to trust the Lord
that is going to encourage us.
Cuz we need God, brethren.
Uh we need him because he's the only
who can touch us where no other person
can touch us. He can touch the innermost
part of us. He can give us the right
encouragement and the true
encouragement,
which satisfies human
human beings. The Lord who is able to
know what you're going through is the
one we are going to trust in this
evening. And so, he's going to do us
good. Shall we pray together as we read
the word of the Lord? Father, in the
name of Jesus,
we want to say thank you this evening.
You've given it unto us that my father
we may draw closer nearer to you. And
you say when you draw closer to you, you
will also draw closer to us. Tonight, we
are thirsting and hungering for you,
Lord.
Come through for us. You know each and
every one of us, and we know what we are
going through. And we pray that Father,
you're going to lift every burden
tonight. You're going to set us free.
You're going to liberate us from any
oppression and suppression of the never
be the same again because the Lord is
here. Bible says Jesus where you
wherever you went you did good. And this
evening he's here with us. By faith we
know because the Bible says where two or
three shall gather in his name there in
their midst he will be. And so he is in
our midst Lord Jesus and you're going to
do us good. May you bless us as we share
the word. May you minister unto us. May
you touch us spirit of God. Elaborate
the word to us. Expose it oh Lord to us.
Give us the wisdom the knowledge hidden
in your word that God in heaven we may
draw your over father the issues of life
from your word in the name of Jesus.
Bless us and be with us for it is in
Jesus' name do we pray.
Amen. Amen. Amen. This evening I want us
to turn to the book of Hebrews.
Um
Hebrews chapter 12. We are reading verse
1 and 2.
Hebrews 12 1 and 2.
I've said we're going to have a moment
of encouragement.
And the Lord is going to do it to us. So
it says
Therefore, since we are surrounded by
such a huge crowd of witnesses
uh to the life of faith
Give me New King James version.
New King James version.
Yes. Therefore, we also, since we are
surrounded by so great a cloud of
witnesses, let us lay aside every weight
and the sin which is so easily ensnares
us.
And let us run with endurance the race
that is set before us. Verse 2.
Looking unto Jesus, the author and the
finisher of our faith,
who for the joy that was set before him
endured the cross, despising the shame,
and has sat down at the right hand
of the throne
of God.
Tonight, I want to share
within the time I've been given
uh on a subject of a title down looking
unto Jesus.
Looking unto Jesus.
When you look at this time we are living
in,
people are involved in so many things,
and people are concerned of so many
things.
Talk to the politicians, they will tell
you, "Me, I'm strategizing for 2027."
That is where their mind is. That is
what they are working day and night.
Some are gathering money here and there,
so that they will have enough money for
their politics come 2027,
though already seemingly it has started.
Talk to the business people.
Those who are not believers, they will
tell you, "Me, I'm looking forward to
the end of the year to make this amount
of money, these millions, and I have
strategized, and I know I'm going
there." He has fixed his eyes on the
business to make this amount of money,
and so forth and so on. People have got
all sorts of concerns
for their lives. Even here,
when we are seated in this auditorium
tonight, every one of us has got a
certain, you know, thing you are eyeing
on. And by the end of the year, you're
saying, "I want to have A, B, C, D." And
there is a power in decision-making,
because most of the things we achieve is
as a result of the decision we make.
And the decision you make, you have to
understand that it can be a negative
decision or a positive decision.
Negative decision will lead you to
negativity.
Positive decision will lead you to
positivity. And so it is up to you and
me to decide the kind of decision I am
going to make.
And when the Bible, I mean the writer
who is
not known
by now, the theologians have not known
the true writer of this book, the
Hebrews.
But somebody is saying, according to the
design,
the people who wrote it either was Paul
or some of his close associates. And
some were saying, or rather some say,
one of them could have been
Barnabas, who was a close associate of
of Paul or even Apollos. So it is not
clear. But the question is, to whom was
it written? And under what circumstances
that
provoked the writer to write to these
people? Uh this
letter
or book was written uh to a group of
believers who were Jews who believed the
Lord Jesus Christ. They came out to out
of Judaism. They forsook the Torah and
the commandments and they believed in
the Lord Jesus Christ. Then when they uh
departed from Judaism, persecution
started. They were facing very severe uh
persecution from their enemies. And so
the writer came up and decided to write
this letter to them to encourage them. I
tell them, "Brethren, what you have
received is the real thing. Don't think
of anything else. Don't depart from the
faith. Stick to Jesus Christ. The
persecutions are there. Your enemies are
running after you day and night, but you
need to understand what you have
received. You should not lose it simply
because it's the real thing. So, the
writer comes and tells them
quite a number of things, but I want us
to look at his There are two words there
I want to us to talk about. There is
look and there is see.
Look
and see. And then we'll move on. When we
are talking of look, it's an action.
When you are purposed to look at
something, you want to have a look at it
until you can describe some features of
the thing you are looking at. You have a
determination. You have made a choice to
look. You have purposed to have, you
know, to look at it and
receive some features in it. There is
something you know. You have made some
deliberate move
to have that thing understood by you
through looking. It is a deliberate
move. You have not been coerced. Nobody
has, I mean,
put you on a task to have a look at it.
It is your choice. That is looking. It
is an action. And what you have to know
is that
me it means directing your attention and
eyes towards something on a purpose. You
direct
your attention. You say, "This is the
attention I'm going to give to this
one." And then you put your eyes on it.
You are towards it that you may, because
there's a purpose as to why you want to
look at it. So, it is very necessary for
us to know. And looking
requires effort. And also intent. It
requires effort. You can get tired when
it comes to looking, but it it
deserves determination, efforts, intent
that you have to look. Why? Because
there are distractors. There are things
that you will make you not to continue
looking. Because looking is an action,
it causes people to get tired. Because
it is not a matter of guessing and then
going. That is something else we are
going to see. So, when it comes to
looking, you have to be determined. You
have to purpose. You have to make sure
that you are going to stick to it until
you get what you want to get from it.
Then,
there is also the word see. That is s e
e. See. This one is about perception.
About perception.
In this one,
it is noticing or perceiving something
with your eyes without actively
trying. That is passive
guessing at something. You just guess at
it passively. You don't have to stick to
it. Actually, you don't have to make a
decision to see something. You are just
Your eyes are caught up and after a few
minutes, the thing goes. I mean, you
don't get some intention to see
something. Something passes, and that's
all. And you may not be able to explain
the features of the thing you have seen.
That is see. And um it is natural and it
is automatic. Seeing is natural. It is
automatic. You don't have to make a
decision to see something. Usually, the
things we see,
I mean, it is an automatic that is
because you have the eyes. And that's
why you have people say, "Ah, eyes we
are meant to see."
Because you don't have to I mean, to
take uh decide to see. it is automatic.
It is natural to see things. And
when we are talking about looking at to
Jesus, we want to do away with the word
see and concentrate on the looking. The
looking. The looking unto Jesus who is
the author and the finisher of our of
our faith.
So, this portion of scripture, which I
want us to do a little exposition about,
to see what is
what is covered in it. What is covered
in We want to have it. We want you to
put it at bare so that we may know what
it can do to us today because the people
it was written to, the first recipients,
we were not there.
But the the word of God is written in a
continuous
tense so that it can apply to any
generation, from any tribe,
any
language. It can apply to anybody. So,
tonight we want us to put ourselves in
the position of the first recipients of
this word.
And we get it as though it was written
to us when we were there or it was
spoken to us when we were there so that
it may help us. So, we want to see a few
things which I'm saying we're going to
do an exposition of some hidden things
in this scripture and see, brethren, at
this dispensation, how we can have this
scripture help us. So, it serves as the
theological climax of Hebrews' discourse
on faith. Now,
this connection, chapter 12, it is
connecting also chapter 11.
Chapter 11. 11, it is where we are
learning about the the the the the
giants of faith. Yeah, the men and women
of faith and we call it the hall of
faith. That is chapter 11 of Hebrews. It
is known as the hall, H A L L of faith.
And so it is connecting so well with the
where the writer starts now chapter 12.
Chapter 12, it is so well networked
because it's talking about faith and uh
how uh the men who conquered in chapter
11, how they walked in faith, the faith
that gave them victory, the faith that
made them to appear in the Bible because
of what they believed the Lord in. So
many of them, actually to be precise,
they are 18 of them. Chapter 11, 13 men
and women of faith, you will get them
there. So the writer now is bringing
those people from chapter 11 to chapter
12 to write to us today.
If we are going to conquer, to
persevere, then we need to look unto
Jesus. What he's saying, those people
did not just conquer, they did not just
overcome. They did it because of the
person who helped them conquer. And the
writer is writing to us today saying we
can also conquer and overcome as they
did uh
the people in chapter 11. They are
there.
Giants of faith, you know?
And uh they are not just there passively
looking at us saying, "Hurry up,
conquer." and so forth. No, they are
well involved in it. They are seeing you
and I and they are wishing that we will
stick to our faith as they stuck and we
conquer as they conquered. I want you to
look an example of a man like Abraham.
Abraham
living in Haran having come from
Mesopotamia
with his father, wife, and his nephew
Lot. Coming to Haran, after a short time
the father dies and the man is there, 75
years of age, no child, no parents. He
is an alien. The man is
devastated in Haran. Actually, his life,
I mean his sun of life is setting. He
has lost hope. No hope for him. He is
waiting to die. But before he died,
there is a God in heaven who saw some
potential in this man who is an
idolater, the potential of bringing out
a nation for God, the nation from whom
the savior would be born. So, God went
for that man whose time is over. He has
nothing and he is there to die. But
quickly God reaches out to him. May the
Lord reach out to you tonight. May he
reach out to you tonight. At the point
of your dispensation, I mean
desperation, at the point of your giving
up, at the point of your you know, hard
moments, may the Lord reach out to you.
So, he reached out to him. Thank God.
Hey, hey. When God got hold of Abraham,
Abraham's life changed in drastically.
The one who was worshipping idols
started worshipping the true God. The
one who had no child became a father of
nations. The one who had no money, I
mean wealth, he became terribly rich.
The one who
was an alien, I mean in a small land of
Haran, became an owner of acres and
acres of land in Canaan. That is the God
we are worshipping. So, that man who
came out of the land to follow God whom
he has heard the very first time, it was
faith. And that is why Hebrew 11 writes
about him. He believed in God that this
God will take me where he wants me to
go. He will give me a child. I will be a
mighty man. This man, the Bible calls
him a prophet also, as well as an army
man. He raised an an army and
he became great in the land. Let me tell
you my brother, my sister, it is not yet
over with you.
Never give up.
The God we serve knows us inside out.
And even when we are here, he knows you.
And he knows what you are going through.
And he's going to come through for you
in Jesus' name. By the way, we are
better than Abraham. Abraham had no God.
He had idols. And today we have a mighty
God, Jesus Christ. After to make the
matter better for us, we have the triune
God in us. We've got the Father, God the
Son, God the Holy Spirit residing in us.
If you did not know, know that today.
Triune God living in you. Powerful
people.
People cannot be conquered by anything.
We are victors in all circumstances and
in all situations to the glory of God.
So, now, in this scripture,
verse one and two,
there is the exposition I talked about I
want us to do. And I want us to look at
some theological weight of the passage
we have talked about and expose some
some ideas hidden in it. And the first
thing is the call to race.
As the first one, I want us to expose.
It is in chapter I mean verse one. It is
in verse one.
The call
to race.
Now, the writer starts by saying
we are surrounded
by witnesses. They are cloud actually a
cloud of witnesses.
Now, when the writer is talking of cloud
of witnesses,
he's drawing some ideas from chapter 11.
And this cloud
I've given three types of them. The
first one is what the writer was writing
about and is about the heroes of faith
in chapter 11. They are surrounding us.
They are seeing you and me and they are
cheering us up that we may conquer and
overcome. And the moment one of us falls
I mean falls off from the race, they are
like, "What have you done?" It's like in
the natural races, if we have got our
our competitor and succeed we um
I mean
we are looking forward for him to win a
gold medal for us and then suddenly he
falls away. Everybody's like, "What has
he done?" And so, these heroes of faith,
they are cheering us up that we continue
with the race. And they are saying,
"Brethren,
me I was thrown in a lion's den
and the same God who delivered me from
that day, he will deliver you. Keep it
up." And they are cheering us up. And
they Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego,
they say, "Look, we were thrown in a
burning fiery furnace having been heated
seven times. We were thrown there and
the God we believed in, he came through
for us. He took us out of the fire. He
will do the same to you." And then they
tell us, "Keep it up, brethren. Move on
in Jesus' name." So, now this cloud, we
have the heroes in chapter 11. Number
two, we have
uh the brethren
as here.
We are also a cloud around one another.
And we are seeing each other. And we are
hoping that all of us wins this race.
Wins this race, all of us one day. We
meet in heaven.
I'm telling you, we wish to each other,
brother, we have got heaven to enter
into. Let us keep it up. Then you say,
you know, there is MBC. Yes, there are
race, but remember, our calling, it is
higher than all these things. And where
we are going, it is better than all
these things. We have eternal life. We
going to live forever. Let us move on.
That's another cloud. And the the other
cloud is the world itself seeing us.
Your workmates,
your uh
I mean, estate mates, name it. Business
people whom you work with. The people
you interact with. That's another cloud.
They have your testimony.
And if I can pause a little, how are you
known out there?
By the sinners.
Do they know you as a brother or a
sister?
Can they give a testimony about yourself
as you interact with them?
Can they say this servant of God, we
know him or her?
She can't do MBCD. When we are doing
MBCD, we isolate her or we isolate him.
She cannot fit. That's another cloud.
Witnesses, people can give a testimony
about yourself.
Brethren, let us know
that the world we are living in.
We are I mean, we are supposed to be
light to the world and a salt to the
world as the Bible says.
But when you look at how we are
behaving,
it is as if we have become the world
ourselves also.
And that is why the world has found some
comfort amongst us.
Some comfort.
When we were getting saved, uh-uh, when
we got saved, many many years ago, so
many of you were not there.
I'm telling you.
You're not there.
Once upon a time,
when you were getting saved,
you would get saved and start looking
for a brother sister because we were
rare.
You could not It was not easy
to get a brother sister. We would walk
kilometers away looking for one believer
to just say praise the Lord or be with a
man.
Yeah, I'm a figure.
What is that sister Lucy? I don't check
him because I know you. We were there
with her.
Many years ago.
Now we don't know what has happened, my
sister.
We don't know what has happened.
That even saying praise the Lord is no
longer there.
I We have been shocked. I meet a brother
I know, praise the Lord.
It's good. It's all right.
Good afternoon.
I mean, people are
shying off from the word of God.
From the faith. They don't want to come
out and say
I will say Christ is my personal savior.
That cloud my brethren, we need to have
the right testimony. We need to come out
and say Jesus is Lord. Really well.
Why? Because he is.
And even if we say he is not, he will
still continue being.
He is the savior. And so those three
clouds are on you. And to bring it
closer to us, how do we know each other?
Okay, see you at Pastor Titus.
You mean you don't want to go back home?
Yeah.
>> I mean
How do we know each other? Amongst
ourselves.
Because we are believers, right?
But how do we know one another?
We are cloud surrounding one another.
When we are singing here in church on
Sunday, Tuesday like today, and when we
call one another in the course of the
week, how we interact when I tell you
come for a cup of tea, what comes into
your mind? And especially if you are of
the opposite sex.
I want to meet you for a cup of tea.
What comes in your mind?
What comes in your mind
is as a result of how we know each other
as a cloud. We surround one another.
And so brethren, let us have the right
testimony. And if there are things that
are making us not to have the right
testimony, let us shed them off.
Hallelujah.
So, this call
of
this cloud, we have to know that those
witnesses are there. You like it or not,
at your place of work, when you are
doing business, in your estate, your
relatives, I mean, they are cloud to
you. So, all the time it's important to
ask yourself, how do they know me?
What kind of a testimony do they they
have about me?
You are a boss for for example, a CEO in
a certain company. How are you known?
As a CEO, H.
And your credentials are written on your
I mean, the door of your office.
But how do people know you?
What testimony can they can they give?
Do they know you as a sister or brother?
How are you known?
Are the people by the people whom you
are leading at your place of work? You
have some people you are in charge of.
How do they describe you?
Hey, hey.
Hallelujah.
The next thing we get in Hebrews 1 is
laying aside weights and sin. Laying
aside weights and
sin. And it says
laying aside
Let us lay aside every weight and the
sin which is so easily ensnares us. And
let us run with endurance the race that
is set before us. So there is weight and
sin. And this sin, it is the sin that
does easily ensnare us.
Now, laying it
aside you need to know
that
this race, or the natural race
I mean, you don't have to go with any
costumes for that race.
There are some specified costumes for
races.
Because if you are going to take part in
a race, you should be light. Number one.
No baggage, no weight that may weigh you
down not to win the race. Because
anybody who gets into a race gets into
it to to do what? To win the race. So
anything that may not make you win the
race, you put it off. And the race we
are in here, brethren, it is the race of
our faith, the journey of faith. We are
on our way to heaven. We are, you know,
running this I mean, this
race towards heaven.
By faith. And the running is day and the
night. And to make the matter better, it
does not matter the number you will be
when we
reach at the end.
You may be the last one, but you'll be
counted a winner. What the Bible wants
here are winners, not number one, number
two, number three.
Winners. So, we have to do what? We have
to lay aside weights.
To run effectively, the believer must
strip away anything that entangles or
hinders spiritual progress. There are so
many things that are hindering brethren
as we walk this journey as we run this
race. There are so many things that
entangles us.
Could be
you have some former
uh
lifestyles, and then you got born again,
and you have been struggling with them.
You are born again, but once in a while
you get yourself followed, I mean, fall
back to them, and after some time you
come back to Christ, and so forth and so
on. I'm telling you you are running this
race, but you are burdened.
And I want to refer you to the book of
Matthew, chapter 11, verse 28. Jesus
said, "Come unto me, all ye that labor."
Continue.
And are heavy laden, and I will do what?
I will give you rest. So, if you feel
you have some baggage, there's a place
you can take them. If there's some
weight that is hindering you from
progressing in this race, that is
distracting you, there is a place you
can cast them unto him, because he is
very faithful. So, it's a matter of
checking in your life.
Deep in your heart,
what is this sin that does easily
ensnare you?
You want to continue some brother, but
sometimes
you get yourself having done what is not
right. That sin is ensnaring you. So,
you should take it off. Well,
you have to understand in our daily
walk, there are those challenges we
face. Temptations are there. Things come
on our way. But when temptations come on
your way of the things you love most,
or rather, the things you loved most
when you were there.
Where? There.
In the world. What you loved most. How
is it now that you are born again?
Hallelujah.
So, those are the things you need to put
into account and ask yourself, could I
be strangling some baggage I had in the
world?
Could there have been something that I
did not conquer when I came to Jesus
Christ? Could there be something that
has made a toll on me that I want to
move on, but this thing draws me
backwards? I want to move forward, but
there's something that is drawing me
backward. My friend, there is no reason
I repeat, there is no reason for you to
get born again, and you are born again.
You are in church, probably you are
serving, and you are struggling with
this sin.
Bad news.
Bad news. It is It's not supposed to be
so. Why? Because salvation is
deliverance.
There is a redemption from your old you.
It is coming out of your old you, the
sinful you.
It is having the power to conquer the
old you.
It is coming out from the old you, and
you put on Christ Jesus, who is the Lord
and the savior. Hallelujah.
>> [screaming]
>> So, that man
is a very dangerous man, by the way.
Let me tell you
very dangerous man. Let's see
Ephesians chapter
chapter four.
Ephesians four.
Amen. Chapter four, verse verse 22.
There's a man we want to see. Verse 22.
That you put off
concerning your former conduct
the old man, not the new man.
Which grows corrupt according to the
deceitful lusts. Now, I want us to have
a a little
uh look
You've talked about look of this
scripture.
Paul is writing to the Ephesians church.
And there are some people who are born
again in the church, but they are still
struggling with the sin. But he's
telling them put off that man
concerning your former conduct because
they got born again and they continue
staying the same conduct in the new
life. And Paul called that conduct the
old man. And he saw them struggling with
the old man.
Which grows corrupt according to the
deceitful
lusts. He is after the things of this
world because that man is not for
heaven.
That man is a dangerous man. If he
controls you, my friend, that man can
take you to hell. But we thank God
because of Jesus Christ. He has given us
victory. He has given us victory to
conquer and overcome. And whenever we
feel we have got some sins that have a
toll in our lives, we have a place to
take them.
To the Lord Jesus Christ. Praise the
Lord.
The
the the worst thing is when you continue
holding on them. And the Lord does not
want that. So, this old man, we need to
do away with him. Why? Because so long
as he's there, you will not have time to
look unto Jesus, the author and the
finisher of your faith. You try to look
unto him. You try to pray. You try to
fast. You try to read the scriptures,
but the old man is not for prayer, not
for fasting, not for study of the word.
The old man is at home. He belongs here.
He is after the pleasures of this world.
He wants to do all things of this world.
He is making you, you know, struggle in
your Christian life. But it is very
important for us to know we have Christ
whom we can look unto. And so this
evening, brethren, I want us to
understand we have a place we can put
our eyes unto. It is in the Lord Jesus
Christ. And then we are told to run with
perseverance endurance. This race needs
people who can endure it. There are
challenges. It is not at tomorrow's end
of a race. My friends,
if some of us God will give us 100
years, will we still be saying the Lord
is my personal savior?
Yes, hallelujah. Thank you, my sister.
Yes, we will. And we should. 100 years,
120 years, you are saying Jesus is still
my personal savior. This is the kind of
believers God is looking forward to. So,
in case you have been feeling as though
you're giving up, don't give up. We have
the Lord Jesus Christ to look upon. And
he's here tonight. He is going to lift
you up. It doesn't matter the kind of
things you are going through. Looking
unto Jesus, the author and the finisher
of our faith. He started that good work
in you, and he will accomplish it. So,
patience, perseverance, endurance is the
key in this race.
Doesn't matter precious, the Lord is
there to conquer and overcome for us.
So, the next thing is focus of the
believer.
That is we focus now on of the believer.
Fixing our eyes on him. This is the
focus. It's now fixing our eyes on to
looking on to him. Yes, I have no money,
but I'm looking on to Jesus. Yes, I am
looking for a job, but my eyes are on to
him. Yes, there is ABCD, but I'm looking
on to Jesus. Even I may be facing some
delays in my life. Things I'm praying
for, things I'm believing the Lord for,
they are not forthcoming, but my eyes
are on the Lord Jesus Christ. So, our
children have no enough school fees, but
my eyes are on you. There is this delay
of this kind of a prayer I've been
praying, but my eyes are in Jesus
Christ. Why? I'm not going to give up.
Because my eyes are there. Looking on to
Jesus, the author and the finisher of
our faith. It it doesn't matter what
happens. The Lord [screaming] is here
with us and he's going to lift you. So,
my brethren, let us put our eyes there
to him because he is the author. He's
the one who started that faith and he
will finish it.
He will bring it to accomplishment.
Then, the other one is the paradigm of
Christ's example.
That is
chapter 2 B says despising the shame and
I sat down at the right hand of the
throne of God. The paradigm uh of
Christ's example.
The joy, when the Bible is talking of
the joy set before him. What is this
joy? Where where did it emanate from?
What was the cause of the joy? Jesus
went to the cross willingly.
And he could see the joy that will be in
the world. He would see his church
established in the world. He could see
the kingdom of God established in the
world. He could see the many believers
who will believe in him after he has
died. So, he went there with a lot of
joy saying as a result of that cross, I
see millions and billions of believers
who will come as a result of my death
there. I see the kingdom of God
established on earth as my being on the
cross. There was a lot of joy.
Do you Do you have the joy of salvation?
Hallelujah. We need to have it. Cuz I
tell people, if you cannot enjoy
salvation, my brother, you've not yet
been saved.
Salvation is enjoyable.
I've been there for some years and I
have tasted it and I have enjoyed it. I
joined it or I entered it when I was a
young man.
17 years.
I'm telling you I cannot regret how I
spent my youth.
Cacius Crusades, name it. [screaming]
That that was my lifestyle.
Crusades, Jesus is Lord. We had no PA
system.
We had no instrumentalists. Macorfee
Kwosoko.
And we are there.
Why? Joy of salvation. We enjoyed it and
that is why we are calling upon every
one of us brethren to purpose to enjoy
salvation.
Really well.
To enjoy salvation. So, Jesus said that
joy he said which was I mean he saw and
the last joy he saw was his being
exalted to heaven after having
conquered. He saw himself exalted to
heaven. That now is the king of kings
and the lord of lords. He's reigning
forever. He saw himself seated there
having you know submitted
I mean brought down the kingdom of
darkness having conquered death having
conquered the grave having said men and
women free. He saw that joy and he
despised
the shame of the cross because the shame
or death of the cross was very shameful.
It is the fools, traitors, and the
murderers who were being taken there and
Jesus had done none of those but he
decided to go there. Let me let me be
that murderer so that the murderers may
be saved. Let me me be that traitor so
that the traitors may be saved. Let me
me be everything. So, he took the shame
of the world upon himself and he went
there willingly very joyously and he
said, "I am dying for the world." And
that is why you are seated where you are
seated because somebody despised the
shame of the cross
for your sake. Praise the living God.
And that's why my brethren we need to
enjoy salvation. We need to be happy
that we are born again. We need to
decide to live a holy life, righteous
life because he who called us is the
righteous, the Lord Jesus Christ. So, as
I conclude I want you to understand that
Jesus went there willingly so that he
may redeem you and me. He despised the
shame and he finally he was exalted to
heaven. Where is he now?
They have said and have sat it down at
the right hand of the throne of God this
evening.
It doesn't matter what is pressing you.
Yes, there's no money. Looking unto
Jesus, the author and the finisher of my
faith. Yes, that
that life partner has delayed, but
looking unto Jesus, the author and the
finisher of my faith. My family has
MBCD, looking unto Jesus, the author and
the finisher of my faith. My business is
not doing well, looking unto Jesus, the
author and the finisher of my faith. I
am not what I thought I would be by now,
but looking unto Jesus, the author of
the author and the finisher of my faith.
And that Jesus will come through for
you.
It will not take too long, brethren. Get
encouraged. Don't fall aside. Don't look
back at all. Don't look back at all
because it is God's will that you and I
may conquer. Amen.
And we are conquerors because he has
called us. He's a conqueror. So now,
listen.
I have no time to touch on what Jesus
told them, certain people.
That nobody
It is in Luke chapter 9.
Luke chapter 9.
We can get that one. 62.
And then I will close.
And to assure you, I'll close. I have
closed.
But I want us to have a look at this. I
want you to have a look at this. Just
say But Jesus said to him, "No one
having put his hand to the plow and
looks and looking back is a fit for the
kingdom of God."
That is settled.
These people he was addressing knew very
well how to plow with oxen and plows.
They knew that.
And they knew the moment you put your
hands on that plow, you can't look back.
Why? You are going to make so many
furrows which are unnecessary.
And he told them after having done that,
my friend, it is not possible. This a
metaphor or fingers of preach of speech
which he used to write this. So, they
knew even me when I'm farming
with the plow, I put my hands on it. I
look back. No, it is it is not possible.
So, he's telling them, as you have
started this journey, my friend, you
can't look back. If you do that, you
will get disqualified as far as the
kingdom of God is concerned. Because
Isaiah 31 is not a fit for the kingdom.
So, brethren, it doesn't matter the
destructors because they are many.
I mean, I cannot tell you they are not
there. There are many destructors in
this faith. They are very many. And if
you want to know, see me in private.
I'll tell you some which I can't say
here. Because they are many. They are
many. And because they are many, we need
to fix our eyes on Jesus. The moment you
take your eyes from Jesus, you are done.
So, no one will ever plow looking
backwards. It's like driving. All of you
are drivers, thank God. So, you know the
moment you put your hands on the
steering wheel and you are on the
highway,
100 km/h, you can't there look back.
Not possible.
You have to look ahead and to see
whether there is a pothole there,
whatever else is there, whether you have
arrived at them
at the set of lights, all that. So, this
person is not fit for the kingdom. But I
thank God because of Jesus Christ, we
are fit for the kingdom of God.
And tonight as we pray, brethren, search
yourself. Let me search myself. Am I
qualified to be in this kingdom? Could
there be some things that have made me
look back as I continue this journey?
Could there be things I'm struggling
with in my life? In my life? And if they
are there, take them to Jesus and you
tell him, "Jesus, from today, looking
unto you, the author and the finisher of
my
God bless you.
>> [applause]
>> Amen. Please rise up. Find a place of
prayer.
We are praying over that word in the
name of Jesus.
Thank the Lord
that he has surrounded you with such a
great multitude of witnesses
in the mighty name of Jesus. Thank God
that you have a place of reference
as you believe God